TAN SOK TING, YUKI

Puchong, Selangor | 012 387 9619 | sokting.tan@gmail.com

Professional Summary

15+ years of product management and software engineering experience, leading Agile, Lean, and Scrum transformations, driving customer loyalty and satisfaction, and optimizing eCommerce and digital transformation initiatives with measurable results.

Skills

- Product strategy, Strategic planning,
 Vision mapping, Competitive Analysis,
 Leadership, Customer Engagement,
 Market Segmentation
- Data Analytics, Google Data Studio, PowerBI
- Process, PRINCE2, Six Sigma, SDLC
- Research market trends, Search engine optimization, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, Google Search Console, Google Data Studio
- Agile, SAFe, Scrum, LeSS, Kanban, Kaizen, Lean, JIT, Extreme Programming

Experience

Product Manager, Digital Innovation TM Research and Development – Cyberjaya

02/2021 to Current

- Managed definition and delivery of Digital Innovation product suite, including Sales Intelligence and Workforce Automation solution and Employee Experience Lifecycle platform with associated priorities, backlogs and communications.
- Defined and developed produce scope, vision, roadmap and strategic plans, delivering high-quality digital solutions.
- Articulated, managed and addressed cross-functional dependencies and monitored KPIs to track results.
- Developed solution hypotheses iteratively, based on user research, industry and market trend analysis.
- Validated and presented business case to C-level executives and led business reviews to guide team progress towards goals.

Scrum Master 07/2020 to 01/2021

K3 Business Technologies – Selangor

- Guided and coached teams to achieve higher agile maturity levels at sustainable and comfortable pace through building cohesive teams and open communication frameworks.
- Educated teams and stakeholders on Large Scale Scrum (LeSS) processes, including product refinement and backlog management, resulting in clear system requirements and improved progress transparency.
- Engaged teams to establish realistic and achievable delivery commitments and supported team members in meeting set goals through monitoring, review and feedback.
- Maintained performance metrics and data that highlighted development progress, product

- quality and output value to stakeholders during review meetings.
- Drive team progress to overcome obstacles and realized success throughout the lifecycle of each iteration.

Marketing IDT Portfolio Manager

06/2019 to 06/2020

British American Tobacco (BAT) – Selangor

- Developed technical aspects of company's strategy to align with business growth and supporting risk management.
- Oversaw technology budget to optimize expenditures and allocate resources.
- Evaluated operational metrics and spearhead process improvements to increase productivity and reduce expenses.
- Facilitated Agile adoption for the organization with the leadership and guided teams with outcome resulting in enhanced performance.
- Supported Brand Management in new initiative and campaign to increase conversions by streamlining processes and system realignments with marketplace, last mile delivery and other eCommerce channels.

Chief Technology Officer

09/2016 to 06/2019

Store and Send Logistics - Selangor

- Developed technical aspects of company's strategy to align with business growth and supporting risk management.
- Oversaw technology budget to optimize expenditures and allocate resources.
- Evaluated operational metrics and spearheaded process improvements to increase productivity and reduce expenses.
- Facilitated Agile adoption for the organization with the leadership and guided teams with outcome resulting in enhanced performance.
- Supported Brand Management in new initiative and campaign to increase conversions by streamlining processes and system realignments with marketplace, last mile delivery and other eCommerce channels.

Product Manager 03/2015 to 09/2016

Ensogo Group – Kuala Lumpur

- Responsible for the management, deployment, and reporting metrics on Ensogo Malaysia eCommerce portal, back-end system, seller center system, customer service, Google Analytics (GA) and Google Tag Manager (GTM).
- Initiated improvement on Alexa traffic ranking, Google page ranking, Search Engine Optimization (SEO), and other channels traffic.
- Performed consumer insights analysis based on demographics, interest, purchase history, predictions from clicks and impressions to develop multi-racial Ensogo SuperMom persona.
- Leads the platform back-end system and mobile app development enabling higher efficiency in content management, order fulfillment and new conversion channel.
- Supported regional initiatives and campaign to increase acquisitions, engagement, and conversions by streamlining processes and system realignments with local digital channels, courier services, and vendor.

Country Product Manager

09/2014 to 03/2015

Asian Room Service – Selangor

• Managed the definition and delivery of the responsive web order system for Room Service

Malaysia and Singapore.

- Conducted market research and analysis to identify customer needs and market trends.
- Established goals and provided direction required to design, develop and deliver technology solutions and supporting processes.
- Leads the new web order system revamp and development for Malaysia and Singapore, for a
 more user-friendly online ordering experience for the hungry and web-savvy consumers. Key
 highlights of the portal revamp include restaurant search by location, improved restaurant and
 menu listing, simplified browsing and order process with 3 steps checkout User Signin/Signup,
 Order Confirmation, and Payment.
- Initiated the development and launch of Customer Ratings and Reviews as well as Online Chat system enabling customer to share their ordering process and food experiences, and immediate customer service responses.

Country Product Manager

06/2014 to 09/2014

Lazada Malaysia – Kuala Lumpur

- Developed high-quality software solutions using programming languages, adhering to coding standards and best practices.
- Leads the intrusion and penetration testing on web application, security risk assessment and Failure Mode Effect Analysis for new data center in New York.
- Coached and mentor cross functional team on User Interface and Experience (UIX) best practices for cross browser compatibility. Also, Initiated web metrics tracking on user behavior and goal tracking using Google Analytics on Fusion platform.
- Member of Jedi Council, a group wide organization CoP overseeing business process improvement, standard operating procedures, and seamless integration of all platforms.
- Recipient of Marketing Forward Award for outstanding performance in UIX to deliver exceptional digital experiences.

Senior Software Developer

07/2010 to 06/2014

Experian - Cyberjaya

- Developed innovative features based on current and future data elements to allow for a more gamification feel to the application.
- Initiated web metrics tracking on heatmap, user behavioral, and conversions using AB Test, CrazzyEgg, and Google Analytics.
- Contributed to code reviews, debugging and optimization.
- Leads Kanban team to resolved application functionalities and integration issues and provide support and troubleshooting as needed.
- Worked within Agile frameworks to consistently meet project timeline and deliverable objectives.

Software Developer

05/2007 to 06/2010

Regent Market Group - Cyberjaya

- Developed innovative features based on current and future data elements to allow for a more gamification feel to the application.
- Initiated web metrics tracking on heatmap, user behavioral, and conversions using AB Test,
 CrazzyEgg, and Google Analytics.
- Contributed to code reviews, debugging and optimization.
- Leads Kanban team to resolved application functionalities and integration issues and provide

- support and troubleshooting as needed.
- Worked within Agile frameworks to consistently meet project timelines and deliverable objectives.

R&D Engineer 10/2005 to 04/2007

JVC Electronics Malaysia – Selangor

- Designed, developed and deployed software to meet business needs.
- Responsible for rapid prototyping and development of digital audio broadcast receiver system, iPod to audio system interfaces, UART data interchanges and communication, and HDMI connection interfaces to Home Theatre System.
- Liaised with cross-functional teams to determine application specifications and technical requirements.
- Successfully completed development and field test for Digital Audio Broadcast module.
- Created training documents on software implementations and user manual for marketed products.

Software Engineer 12/2004 to 09/2005

NEC Machinery – Selangor

- Designed, developed and deployed software to meet business needs.
- Modified existing software by correcting errors and upgrading interfaces for improved performance.
- Collaborated with engineering team members to optimize software or hardware interfaces.
- Provided technical support to users and Product Support personnel in addressing customer issues.
- Created detailed specification documents on the software implementations.

Software Engineer 08/2003 to 09/2004

Muehlbauer Technologies - Melaka

- Applied working knowledge of software lifecycle to develop and lead software efforts.
- Designed, developed and deployed software for Die Sorter and Waffle Pack machine applications.
- Updated existing software to resolve errors and adapt to new performance requirements.
- Focused on troubleshooting interoperability and application issues.
- Liaised with cross-functional teams to determine application specifications and technical requirements.

Education

BENG(H): Electronics and Computing

Aug 2003

The Nottingham Trent University (In collaboration with KBU International College) - Selangor

Diploma: Computer Engineering

Jan 2001

Institut Teknologi Pertama - Kuala Lumpur

Languages

English, Fluent

Bahasa Melayu, Fluent

Cantonese, Conversational

Certifications

- Certified Professional Agile Coaching ICP-ACC
- Certified SAFe 5 Product Owner/Product Manager
- Certified SAFe 5 Practitioner
- Certified SAFe 5 Agilist
- Professional Scrum Product Owner II (PSPO II)
- Professional Scrum Product Owner I (PSPO I)
- Professional Scrum Master I (PSM I)
- Agile Master Certified (SAMC)
- Scrum Product Owner Certified (SPOC)
- Scrum Master Certified (SMC)
- Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC)
- Digital marketing (SCDM-A)
- PRINCE2 Practitioner
- Six Sigma Green Belt
- ITIL Foundation v3
- IT Architect (CITA-F)